Charlotte Coffyn Wilkinson Bragdon Papers, 1890-1962
Smith College Archives
Charlotte Coffyn Wilkinson Bragdon Papers
1890-1962
Bragdon, Charlotte Coffyn Wilkinson
RG 80. Class of 1894.
1 box (2.5 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The papers are largely letters from Charlotte Coffyn Wilkinson Bradgon, Class of 1884, to Charlotte May Wilkinson, her mother, with additional letters containing information on her life.
Charlotte Coffyn Wilkinson Bradgon was the daughter of Alfred and Charlotte May Wilkinson. Her mother was the daughter of Samuel J. May and was first cousin to Louisa May Alcott, and all were involved with the anti-slavery movement. Ms. Wilkinson graduated from Smith College (Class of 1894) and eventually settled in New York City where she was employed at the Henry Street Settlement. She later became the national secretary and then president of the National League of Women Workers. In 1902 she married Claude Fayette Bragdon, an architect in Rochester, New York and lived in that city. Her son, Henry W. Bragdon, was born September 6, 1906. On December 16, 1907 she died suddenly.
The papers consist primarily of letters from Charlotte to her mother, Charlotte May Wilkinson (Mrs. Alfred Wilkinson and sometimes referred to in the letters as "dearest Marmee") and other materials that relate to Ms. Wilkinson's short life. Her letters to her mother do provide a rich source of information on life at Smith College during her student years.
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The papers are open for research according to the regulations of the Smith College Archives without any additional restrictions.
History of the Collection
The papers of Charlotte Coffyn Wilkinson Bradgon (Class of 1894) were donated over a period of time to the Smith College Archives from a variety of sources.
Additional Information
Related Material
Researchers should also view:
80. Class of 1894 Records
"In Memoriam-Chalotte Wilkinson Bragdon," Smith College Monthly 15 (Feb. 1908): 324-325.
Chauncey, Laurie Worcester. "Charlotte Wilkinson's Letters," Smith Alumnae Quarterly 52 (Feb. 1961): 80-83.
- General materials 1900-1961 (Box 1495, Folder 1)
- Eulogies 1907-1908 (Box 1495, Folder 2)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson 1890-1891 (Box 1495, Folder 3)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson Jan 1892-Apr 1892 (Box 1495, Folder 4)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson May 1892-June 1892 (Box 1495, Folder 5)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson Oct 1892-Dec 1892 (Box 1495, Folder 6)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson 1893 (Box 1495, Folder 7)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson 1895-1898 (Box 1495, Folder 8)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson 1903-1904 (Box 1495, Folder 9)
- Correspondence of Charlotte Wilkinson 1905-1907 (Box 1495, Folder 10)
- Correspondence to Josephine Wilkinson 1908, undated (Box 1495, Folder 11)
- Correspondence of Claude F. Bragdon 1900-1908 (Box 1495, Folder 12)
- Correspondence of Henry W. Bragdon 1960-1962 (Box 1495, Folder 13)
- Photographs 1890s-1907 (Box 1495, Folder 14)